<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.MiracleForge.cosmic-ext-marketwatch</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <name>Marketwatch</name>
  <summary>Real-time stock market ticker extention for the COSMIC desktop</summary>


  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/MiracleForge/cosmic-ext-marketwatch</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/MiracleForge/cosmic-ext-marketwatch/issues</url>

  <icon type="stock">com.github.MiracleForge.cosmic-ext-marketwatch</icon>

  <update_contact>paulomoreirarosado@hotmail.com</update_contact>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.MiracleForge.cosmic-ext-marketwatch.desktop</launchable>

  <description>
    <p>Cosmic Marketwatch is an ext applet designed for the COSMIC desktop environment that provides real-time tracking of financial market data. It is lightweight, responsive, and fully integrated into the desktop panel, allowing users to monitor stock prices, cryptocurrencies, and other assets without opening a dedicated application.</p>

    <p>The applet presents symbols and values in a clean and minimal interface, with support for price changes and color indicators reflecting gains or losses. This makes it quick and intuitive to read, ideal for users who want to keep track of the market throughout the day without distractions.</p>

    <p>It also includes configuration options to customize tracked assets, adjust layout (horizontal or vertical), and choose between icon-only or detailed display modes. It is a practical tool for traders, investors, and anyone interested in keeping market data always visible.</p>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Market data overview</caption>
      <image>https://github.com/MiracleForge/cosmic-ext-marketwatch/raw/main/screenshots/cosmic-ext-marketwatch-wallet.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Settings panel</caption>
      <image>https://github.com/MiracleForge/cosmic-ext-marketwatch/raw/main/screenshots/cosmic-ext-marketwatch-settings.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

<developer id="com.github.miracleforge">
  <name>MiracleForge</name>
</developer>

<provides>
  <binary>cosmic-ext-marketwatch</binary>
</provides>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </requires>

  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>X-COSMIC</category>
  </categories>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-04-17">
      <description>
        <p>New market screens and navigation improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added multiple market screens: Most Active, Gainers, and Losers</li>
          <li>Introduced tab-based navigation for switching between market views</li>
          <li>Redesigned caching system to cache data per screen and wallet</li>
          <li>Improved navigation behavior to avoid unnecessary reloads</li>
          <li>Renamed "Trending" to "Market Overview"</li>
          <li>Refined section headers with improved typography and accent color usage</li>
          <li>Improved spacing and layout consistency across settings</li>
          <li>Adjusted refresh controls spacing for better usability</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-03-25">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance update and improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixes in <code>app.metainfo.xml</code> for Cosmic Store validation</li>
          <li>Adjusted categories and icon for AppStream compatibility</li>
          <li>Improvements to documentation and package metadata</li>
          <li>Change applet name for trademark policy</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-03-20">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of Cosmic Ext Marketwatch.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Real-time market data from Yahoo Finance (no API key required)</li>
          <li>Current price and percentage change displayed directly in the panel</li>
          <li>Automatic rotation between multiple assets</li>
          <li>Detailed popup with tabbed interface: Overview, Wallet, Alerts, and Settings</li>
          <li>Configurable alerts: price thresholds, percentage changes, and trend changes</li>
          <li>Desktop notifications when alert conditions are met</li>
          <li>Latest news per asset via Yahoo Finance</li>
          <li>Support for multiple currencies: USD, BRL, EUR, GBP, JPY, CHF, CAD, AUD, CNY, INR</li>
          <li>Configurable update interval and rotation speed</li>
          <li>Persistent configuration for portfolios and alerts</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>stocks</keyword>
    <keyword>finance</keyword>
    <keyword>market</keyword>
    <keyword>ticker</keyword>
    <keyword>COSMIC</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
